Peru is waiting for a formal election result after a long and disputed presidential count.
Al Jazeera reported that right-wing candidate Keiko Fujimori is ahead after electoral authorities finished reviewing contested ballots.
The final tally gave her a very narrow lead over leftist rival Roberto Sanchez, who has refused to recognise the result.
Peru's National Jury of Elections is expected to make an official announcement on July 3.
Fujimori is one of the country's best-known and most divisive politicians.
She is the daughter of former President Alberto Fujimori, whose rule still divides Peru because supporters credit him with restoring order, while critics point to corruption and human rights abuses.
Her latest campaign promised unity and stronger security, but a close vote means the next government could begin under heavy pressure.
The situation matters beyond Peru because Latin America has seen repeated elections where economic frustration, crime and distrust of institutions produce very tight results.
Even after votes are counted, legitimacy can remain uncertain.
Neighbouring governments will watch whether the next president can govern without deepening the country's split.