Europe is often described as dependent on China, especially for batteries, rare earth materials, solar equipment and many consumer goods.
A new Euronews analysis argues that the relationship is more complicated.
China also still needs European technology in several strategic sectors, including advanced semiconductor tools, aviation, pharmaceuticals, robotics and some automotive chips.
For the EU, this matters because trade tensions with Beijing are rising, while European governments are debating how to reduce risk without starting a damaging trade war.
Brussels wants more secure supply chains, but it also knows that European companies earn money from selling equipment, expertise and maintenance services to China.
The difficult question is whether these strengths can give Europe real bargaining power.
Experts quoted by Euronews are cautious.
They say China's control over rare earths remains a much stronger pressure point, while European leverage is spread across private companies and complex supply chains.
The story shows why EU-China trade policy is becoming less about cheap goods and more about strategic dependence.
For learners, the key phrase is strategic dependence: countries may trade freely, yet still fear losing access to essential technology.