A human drama is unfolding in Venezuela after two powerful earthquakes struck shortly after a deportation flight arrived from the United States.
Al Jazeera, citing AP and Reuters reporting, said more than 140 people had been deported to Venezuela on the same day.
Some were taken to a hotel in La Guaira, one of the hardest-hit areas, and rescue workers are now searching the rubble for survivors.
Venezuela says the earthquakes killed more than 1,700 people across the country.
Survivors described escaping collapsed buildings, walking through damaged streets and trying to contact relatives after communications failed.
The story has become highly visible online because it combines natural disaster, migration policy and personal survival.
It also raises difficult questions about how governments manage deportations during unstable conditions.
The United States has increased removals to many countries, while humanitarian groups warn that deported people can be especially vulnerable when they arrive without support.
In this case, the timing turned a routine deportation flight into a tragedy.
The victims are not only statistics; many were caught between two governments and a collapsing local emergency.